<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning and Visual Perception | Academic</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/machine-learning-and-visual-perception/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/machine-learning-and-visual-perception/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Machine Learning and Visual Perception</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Machine Learning and Visual Perception</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/machine-learning-and-visual-perception/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>e) Machine learning and visual perception</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/external-project-copy-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/external-project-copy-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project develops an efficient mask detection system using Python, designed to autonomously identify whether individuals are wearing masks. Originating from the global COVID-19 pandemic in 2019, the context highlights the necessity of mask-wearing in public areas and the urgent need for automated systems to reduce the burden on manual checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development-tools-and-technical-approach&#34;&gt;Development Tools and Technical Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizing the Python IDE PyCharm and the image annotation tool Labelme as primary development and data processing tools, the project employs machine learning algorithms—specifically, the MobileNet framework—for in-depth training and optimization. Experimental methods include data preprocessing, model training, and testing validation, ensuring the system&amp;rsquo;s accuracy and practicality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code Implementation and Performance Optimization
The summary details the process from data set construction and model architecture establishment to the implementation of training strategies, emphasizing optimization measures taken during model training, such as dynamic learning rate adjustments and early stopping. These measures significantly enhance the model&amp;rsquo;s generalization ability and recognition accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results-display-and-application-value&#34;&gt;Results Display and Application Value&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental outcomes demonstrate the system&amp;rsquo;s effective recognition of mask-wearing status in real-time video streams, validating the model&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness. The mask detection system not only achieves the technical objectives but also holds significant application potential in the field of public health management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project showcases the powerful application capabilities of deep learning in the public health domain, particularly against the backdrop of the current global pandemic. The development of the mask detection system bears important social value and practical significance. With continuous technological advancement and optimization, the system is expected to play a larger role in a broader range of scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summary aims to provide web viewers with a clear, professional perspective on the project&amp;rsquo;s core values and technical details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
