<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronic System Design | Academic</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/electronic-system-design/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/electronic-system-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Electronic System Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Electronic System Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/electronic-system-design/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>f) Electronic system design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/external-project-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/external-project-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-background&#34;&gt;Project Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intelligent vehicle, or wheeled mobile robot, integrates multiple functions such as environmental sensing, planning and decision-making, and autonomous driving into a comprehensive system. Aimed at enhancing future lifestyles with smarter solutions, this technology is applicable not only in military contexts but also in scientific research, intelligent rescue, and more. The vehicle&amp;rsquo;s mechanical structure comprises the body, wheels, speed sensors, rotational axles, equipped with a power driver and a camera module for environmental data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-scheme-overview&#34;&gt;Design Scheme Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employing a PID control algorithm and a CCD linear camera for black line guidance detection, processed by an LM393 comparator for microcontroller-based data collection and image recognition, this design enables path identification. Motor drive is facilitated by the PC33886 model, with speed measured by direct photoelectric sensors, and data displayed on an LCD screen. Four button keys are utilized for parameter settings, enhancing the user interface for onsite debugging. The project ingeniously incorporates a mix of photonic, mechanical, and wireless communication technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;structural-and-system-design&#34;&gt;Structural and System Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the principles of autonomous guide robot systems, the intelligent car is capable of autonomously recognizing and following predetermined paths. The main control module uses the STC89C51 microcontroller, focusing on centralized control and modular design, incorporating infrared sensor line tracking and trajectory detection modules. The mechanical structure is designed to minimize external light interference, ensuring balanced and stable navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware-system-construction&#34;&gt;Hardware System Construction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system&amp;rsquo;s hardware includes the STM32F103 microcontroller as the main control module, along with power, motor drive, infrared obstacle avoidance, control terminal, and wireless video monitoring modules. This setup ensures reliable power supply and effective control over the vehicle&amp;rsquo;s dynamic monitoring functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-challenges-and-solutions&#34;&gt;Programming Challenges and Solutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report also delves into the learning process for programming the STM32 microcontroller, including clock initialization, mobility function implementation, PID algorithm development, steering functionality, Bluetooth serial port configuration, and PID debugging. By exploring sensor detection, PWM output for motor driving, speed detection, and serial communication, the project overcame various developmental challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-summary&#34;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through teamwork, we successfully assembled the intelligent car and achieved the line-tracking task. Throughout the project, we solved multiple technical problems, gaining an in-depth understanding of the working principles of intelligent cars and mastering STM32 related skills. This experience not only enhanced our practical abilities but also strengthened our team collaboration spirit. This course has provided us with invaluable and enriching learning, contributing significantly to our academic and practical growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
