<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation &amp; Entrepreneurship Training Program for College Students | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/innovation-entrepreneurship-training-program-for-college-students/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/innovation-entrepreneurship-training-program-for-college-students/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Innovation &amp; Entrepreneurship Training Program for College Students</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Innovation &amp; Entrepreneurship Training Program for College Students</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/innovation-entrepreneurship-training-program-for-college-students/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>b) Innovation &amp; Entrepreneurship Training Program for College Students</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable blind people to perceive surrounding obstacles in real-time while traveling and improve the safety of blind people&amp;rsquo;s travel, traditional blind walking sticks have been modified. This article adopts the STM32f103zet6 microcontroller and uses embedded development design to add functions such as ultrasonic obstacle avoidance, GPS positioning, fall detection, fingerprint unlocking, and voice broadcasting to the traditional blind cane. This project utilizes the XFS5152CE chip to achieve voice broadcasting function, the AS608 optical fingerprint module to achieve fingerprint unlocking function, the ESP8266WiFi module to achieve interaction between mobile phones and intelligent guide canes, the ADXL345 module to detect the user&amp;rsquo;s status in real-time, and to achieve fall warning function. The ultrasonic obstacle avoidance module utilizes the principle of ultrasonic ranging. The GPS positioning module can receive and demodulate the broadcast C/A code signal of satellites, and achieve GPS positioning function by calculating the pseudo distance to each satellite and calculating parameters such as longitude and latitude. The feasibility of this scheme has been verified through experiments. Fingerprint unlocking, voice broadcasting, and GPS positioning functions can all operate normally. When the distance between the guide rod and the obstacle is less than 0.2m, or the forward acceleration in a certain direction of the guide rod is too large, the intelligent guide rod can send out a warning signal in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;key-words-stm32-microcontroller-intelligent-blind-cane-ultrasonic-ranging-gps-embedded&#34;&gt;KEY WORDS: STM32 microcontroller, intelligent blind cane, ultrasonic ranging, GPS, embedded&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;11-project-overview&#34;&gt;1.1 Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.1.1 Introduction to the Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the assistive tools for mobility, guide canes are widely used among the blind community. In today&amp;rsquo;s technologically advanced world, the trend towards product intelligence is undeniable. Taking into consideration the overall environment of the pandemic and the daily mobility needs of the blind, this project is dedicated to designing an intelligent guide cane to further facilitate the mobility of the blind. By adding only a small amount of cost, the guide cane is equipped with an ultrasonic obstacle avoidance system, a GPS positioning system, a fall detection with one-click alarm feature, a display screen that can show personal health codes and payment codes, a voice broadcast for daily weather forecasts, and a fingerprint lock to protect important personal information such as health codes and payment codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-project-plan&#34;&gt;1.2 Project Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.2.1 Background of the Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to statistics from the Ministry of Health, there are as many as 14 million blind people in China, making it the country with the highest number of blind individuals in the world. On average, there is one blind person in every 100 individuals. Every year, about 450,000 new cases of blindness and visually impaired individuals are reported in China, highlighting an urgent need to address their mobility issues. The factors affecting the lives of the blind mainly include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the physical defects of the blind lead to many disadvantages in their lives;
Second, due to mobility challenges, the blind find it difficult to interact with the outside world, lacking in entertainment and social interactions.
Third, due to their physical disabilities, the blind face unequal treatment in social work and interpersonal interactions compared to sighted individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to visual impairments, the blind community has developed a communication mode different from sighted individuals for perceiving the world and conveying information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys show that only 27% of blind individuals go out daily, 55% of them are unable to distinguish directions while traveling, and 34% worry about colliding with obstacles during their journeys. The survey concluded that the main reason for the low mobility of blind individuals is the lack of a comprehensive transportation system and friendly navigation devices, along with the low utilization rate of blind paths. There is a general desire among the blind for friendly mobility tools to ensure their safety, a dedicated transportation system for the blind, and the introduction of high-tech products for better navigation and assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.2.2 Significance of the Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the inability of the blind to easily venture outdoors hinders their interaction with the external world. Products such as blind navigators can facilitate their mobility, increase safety, and make their travels less tedious, thereby helping blind individuals integrate into modern intelligent life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, in the context of big data, artificial intelligence, and 5G, relying on advanced scientific and technological means to solve the mobility issues of the blind is of great significance. The blind hope to be treated equally by others, to not be isolated, and to participate in social life and activities just like sighted people. Hence, there is a strong desire for optimized, companion-style mobility devices. Only by solving the issues of independent, unobstructed, and safe travel for the blind, and by providing convenient services to help them integrate into modern intelligent life, can blind individuals feel more dignified and achieve higher life satisfaction. Therefore, from a humanitarian perspective, designing more advanced mobility products for the blind is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.2.3 Existing Basis of the Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guide cane developed by Gao RX and others in the United States utilizes ultrasonic sensors to specifically detect obstacles within 5 meters in front of the user&amp;rsquo;s head; Mohapatra S and colleagues in India used three ultrasonic sensors to simultaneously detect obstacles directly ahead, underground in front, and slightly above in front; Hongping Ma and others from Tongji University developed an infrared detection guide cane with a dual voice alarm system using a buzzer and an MP3 module to guide blind people to walk quickly and safely; Kehua Zhang and others developed a guide system based on a single Kinect sensor (as shown in Figure 1), which can use depth image inversion algorithms and obstacle recognition algorithms to simultaneously detect all ground obstacles, pits, and hanging obstacles within a height of the blind person, a width of 1 meter, and a distance of 3 meters, and plan the best obstacle avoidance route within 3 meters based on the type and distance of each obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, after comprehensively evaluating the existing guide products on the market, we decided to use the intelligent guide cane as the carrier, linking traditional intelligent guide canes with intelligent terminals to create a guide cane with more powerful functions, more humanized design, and more conducive to improving the quality of life for people with visual impairments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;13-objectives-and-main-content-of-the-project&#34;&gt;1.3 Objectives and Main Content of the Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main content of this research includes adding features such as weather forecasting, ultrasonic obstacle avoidance, GPS positioning, fall detection, fingerprint unlocking, and the display of health codes and payment codes to a standard guide cane. It also includes voice broadcasting of relevant information. The fall detection module uses sensing devices to detect the angle between the cane and the ground, and sends the corresponding angle information to the controller. The controller controls the module to signal and alert passersby to assist the blind person, thus achieving the function of fall alarm. Ultrasonic obstacle avoidance determines the presence and distance of obstacles by detecting the return of sound waves. The GPS positioning module can send a text message with location information to a family member&amp;rsquo;s mobile phone after obtaining the latitude and longitude. By entering STA mode, the WiFi module can connect to a router or mobile hotspot to upload data to the cloud platform. By opening the app associated with the cloud platform on a mobile phone, communication between the mobile phone and the intelligent guide cane can be achieved. Guide cane users can send requests to the mobile phone for weather forecasts, health codes, and payment codes. After receiving the request, the mobile end sends back corresponding health code, payment code screenshot data, and weather data. Upon receiving the data, the microprocessor on the cane side performs data processing work and then transmits the processed information to the corresponding information display device, such as a screen or the speaker of the voice synthesis module. Finally, to prevent personal information such as payment codes from being misused, the fingerprint recognition module sends the input fingerprint information to the microcontroller. The microcontroller matches the input fingerprint information with the fingerprint information previously recorded, thereby achieving the purpose of fingerprint verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;14-summary-of-innovative-features-of-the-project&#34;&gt;1.4 Summary of Innovative Features of the Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main achievements of this research utilize the STM32 microcontroller, embedded development design, signal processing, and other technologies to develop a new type of guide cane, which has certain technological innovation value. Our design connects the mobile phone with the guide cane, displaying health codes and payment codes on the guide cane, and cooperates with the voice module to broadcast during payment, facilitating the blind during the epidemic for convenience and payment security, with certain technological innovation and market value. This research is primarily aimed at individuals with visual impairments. Currently, blind people mainly rely on guide dogs and traditional guide canes for outdoor activities. The results of this research can enrich the mobility methods of blind people, greatly facilitate their lives, and have certain social innovation value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;theoretical-research&#34;&gt;Theoretical Research&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;21-ultrasonic-obstacle-avoidance&#34;&gt;2.1 Ultrasonic Obstacle Avoidance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.1.1 Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design idea of the ultrasonic obstacle avoidance program is based on the principle of ultrasonic ranging. Initially, the microcontroller sends a high-level signal lasting 20us to the Trig terminal of the ultrasonic module, followed by a low-level signal, activating the ultrasonic module. The module then emits eight 40Khz square wave pulses and waits for the signal to return. If a signal returns, the Echo terminal of the ultrasonic module outputs a high-level signal. The duration of the high-level signal reception equals the time taken for the ultrasonic waves to travel from emission to reception. The distance to the obstacle is calculated as (time of high-level signal reception * 340) / 2, measured in meters. By taking multiple measurements from different directions in front of the guide cane and performing multiple samplings, the data error is minimized. Finally, the microcontroller processes the data to prompt obstacle avoidance alerts. The HC-SR04 ultrasonic module, commonly used in robotics for obstacle avoidance, object measurement, liquid level detection, public security, and parking space detection, primarily consists of two general-purpose piezoelectric ceramic ultrasonic sensors with peripheral signal processing circuits.
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/TmQu1pgL7nvVdNf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

The module has one sensor for emitting ultrasonic signals and another for receiving the ultrasonic signals that bounce back. Due to the weak nature of both the emitted and received signals, it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to use external signal amplifiers to enhance the power of the emitted signal and amplify the reflected signal for stable transmission to the microcontroller.
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/YG5UuDeIC1TKx3V.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

2.1.2 Module Parameters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/nkOfXGzWPdDwTbQ.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;3.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.1.3 Module Pins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultrasonic module has four pins: Vcc, Trig (control terminal), Echo (reception terminal), and GND. The VCC and GND are connected to a 5V power supply. The Trig (control terminal) controls the emission of ultrasonic waves, while the Echo (reception terminal) receives the reflected ultrasonic waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.1.4 Implementation Effect of the Ultrasonic Module
To evaluate the performance of the ultrasonic module, a series of experiments were conducted. These experiments tested the intelligent cane&amp;rsquo;s application scenarios, including its ability to recognize and alert against various obstacles. The module could accurately identify obstacles and, in conjunction with the voice broadcast module, alert the user, proving its reliability. The experiments showed that the ultrasonic module successfully ensured that users of the guide cane could avoid obstacles safely while walking, maintaining error within an acceptable range. This experiment applied the ultrasonic module to the guide cane, effectively detecting the environment and promptly identifying obstacles around the blind, providing a safeguard for their safe and rapid movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;22-fingerprint-recognition-module&#34;&gt;2.2 Fingerprint Recognition Module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.2.1 Principle
The fingerprint recognition module based on the STM32 microcontroller uses the AS608 optical fingerprint module, which operates at 3.3V. The default system password for the fingerprint module is 0, and its default address is 0Xffffffff, which can be modified through commands. It&amp;rsquo;s important to ensure that the address field in the data packet matches this address.
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/fIxMsNm497eXqpb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;4.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

Initially, it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to initialize the UART, delay functions, and clock of the STM32, followed by interrupt priority grouping. After the STM32 and AS608 module handshake, establishing a connection between the STM32 and AS608, the connection result is displayed on the screen. Upon successful connection, the AS608&amp;rsquo;s library fingerprint numbers and relevant parameters are read. Successful reading triggers a command to record fingerprints. The status of PS_Sta is checked; if PS_Sta instruction equals 1, it indicates that a finger is pressed down, starting the fingerprint scanning process, and the display shows “Please press fingerprint.” Once pressed, AS608 generates a feature image stored in CharBuffer1 or CharBuffer2. This process is repeated for the second time. If the comparison fails, the input is requested again; if successful, it indicates that the fingerprint image generation is successful. The system then automatically assigns an ID to the fingerprint feature image for template storage. For unlocking with the fingerprint module, it&amp;rsquo;s only necessary to search the fingerprint database for a matching fingerprint to score, and if the score reaches the set standard value, the unlocking is successful.
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/3rEcu9ih2UYL5Fa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;5.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

2.2.2 Implementation Effect of the Fingerprint Recognition Module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assess the performance of the fingerprint recognition module, several experiments were conducted. These experiments aimed at various application scenarios of the intelligent cane, including recognizing different individuals&amp;rsquo; fingerprints. The module could accurately identify the user&amp;rsquo;s fingerprint for unlocking, while non-user fingerprints triggered an alarm. The results showed that the fingerprint recognition module successfully ensured the information security of the guide cane users, with errors maintained within acceptable limits. This experiment applied the fingerprint recognition module to the guide cane, effectively detecting the user&amp;rsquo;s fingerprint, converting the fingerprint image into a digital signal, and comparing it with the fingerprint template stored in the database, achieving identity verification and recognition functions, effectively ensuring the safety of the guide cane use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;23-voice-broadcast-module&#34;&gt;2.3 Voice Broadcast Module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.3.1 Hardware Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section employs the XFS5152CE chip produced by iFlytek, which utilizes a TTS (Text-to-Speech) voice module. Not only can this chip perform real-time voice broadcasting, but it also has the capability for voice recognition. However, since our product currently does not require voice recognition capabilities, we will focus solely on the voice broadcasting function. The XFS5152CE chip supports UART, I2C, and SPI interfaces for communication, allowing it to receive commands and data from a host device through UART, I2C, or SPI interfaces. The maximum length of data that can be sent is 4K bytes. During voice broadcasting, we use the UART interface for communication, ensuring the baud rate of the module&amp;rsquo;s communication matches that of the host device or the microcontroller (STM32f103zet6). The host device sends a start decoding command to the voice chip, which then decodes the received audio data and plays it in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.3.2 Software Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process begins with initializing the serial port, where the baud rate is set via a dip switch. Following this, output pins are initialized. The BSY pin indicates the current working status: a low level represents the Ready state, while a high level indicates Busy. By connecting one of the microcontroller&amp;rsquo;s GPIOs to this pin, we can read the input state of this IO to determine the module&amp;rsquo;s current operating status. Next, we encapsulate the voice broadcast function, where the control identifier needs to be sent in the format of voice synthesis commands, meaning the synthesis command comprises “frame header + data area length + synthesis command word + text encoding format + control marker text.” In coding, we encapsulate the required command words. The XFS5152CE chip&amp;rsquo;s voice synthesis function supports various text control markers, allowing users to set the voice, volume, speed, and tone. The format for text control markers typically involves lowercase letters and Arabic numerals within square brackets (i.e., &amp;ldquo;[]&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;24-fall-detection-module&#34;&gt;2.4 Fall Detection Module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.1 Hardware Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design utilizes the ADXL345 module for real-time detection of the user&amp;rsquo;s status. This module can measure both static gravitational acceleration for tilt detection and dynamic acceleration caused by motion. It is capable of detecting tilt changes within 1 degree. The module includes features for activity/inactivity detection, tap detection, and free-fall detection. Coupled with a buzzer alarm system, it can detect falls and promptly sound an alarm, with a button to cancel false alarms if necessary. The ADXL supports standard I2C or SPI digital interfaces, features a 32-level FIFO buffer, and offers various motion detection and flexible interrupt modes. With a resolution of up to 13 bits and several measurement ranges, it&amp;rsquo;s highly sensitive, capable of measuring tilt changes less than 1°, and efficiently executes the fall detection function. The sensor&amp;rsquo;s low power consumption, at just 0.1μA in standby mode, and its small size (3mm5mm1mm LGA package) make it ideal for integration into the guide cane, minimizing packaging costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.2 Software Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ADXL345&amp;rsquo;s SCL, SDA, INT1, and INT2 pins are connected to the STM32&amp;rsquo;s PB6, PB7, PB10, and PB11 pins, respectively, facilitating communication via the I2C protocol. The focus is placed on initializing the ADXL345, setting high and low thresholds, and determining the condition based on the threshold and duration to autonomously judge the sensor&amp;rsquo;s state. Two modes are configured: one for detecting static events during motion, where the ADXL345 evaluates whether it&amp;rsquo;s below the low threshold for a specified duration, sending a pulse signal to the INT1 pin if detected, and another for detecting motion events when stationary, where the ADXL345 sends a pulse to the INT2 pin if acceleration in any direction exceeds the high threshold. External interrupts on rising edges are used to distinguish between the PB10 and PB11 pins, avoiding immediate entry into sleep mode to prevent potential wake-up issues. A low-power mode, stop mode, is employed to extend sensor standby time, halting the clock and core, with any external interrupt capable of awakening the mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.3 Implementation Effect of the Fall Detection Module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A series of experiments were conducted to evaluate the fall detection module&amp;rsquo;s performance under various scenarios and angles, ensuring its accuracy and reliability. The module could correctly identify falls and promptly alert passersby, with errors maintained within an acceptable range. This application of the fall detection module in the guide cane significantly enhances user safety and accident prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;25-gps-module&#34;&gt;2.5 GPS Module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.5.1 Hardware Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorporating GPS technology into the intelligent cane as an assistive device offers precise positioning and navigation capabilities, enhancing the mobility experience for individuals with mobility impairments. This study aims to design a GPS module based on the STM32 microcontroller that achieves accurate positioning and navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, through meticulous hardware selection and design, a GPS module suitable for cane applications was chosen, alongside the design of connection interfaces and antenna circuits for the STM32 microcontroller. Following the GPS module&amp;rsquo;s operational principles and protocols, a driver program and data parsing algorithm were developed for the STM32. Various experiments confirmed the module&amp;rsquo;s performance and accuracy across different environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hardware design, after evaluating available GPS modules for size, power consumption, and compatibility, a module was selected. It&amp;rsquo;s a standalone hardware device comprising an antenna and receiver, requiring connection to the STM32 via UART for data transmission. Based on the chosen GPS module, a power management circuit and signal transmission circuit were designed to ensure stable operation and accurate signal transmission. An excellent GPS antenna was selected and its layout optimized to enhance reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.5.2 Software Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In software design, a driver program was developed to facilitate communication between the STM32 and the GPS module, ensuring smooth data transfer and communication. According to the GPS module&amp;rsquo;s output data format, a parsing algorithm was written to convert raw data into useful location information such as longitude, latitude, and altitude. To improve positioning accuracy and stability, filtering algorithms and data correction techniques were employed to process and optimize GPS data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using satellite signals, the STM32 can calculate the device&amp;rsquo;s geographical location through triangulation, measuring the time difference and signal propagation time from various satellites. The GPS module&amp;rsquo;s data, processed by the STM32, can be combined with other sensor data, such as obstacle detection, to provide more precise navigation and environmental awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.5.3 Implementation Effect of the GPS Module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a series of experiments testing the smart cane in different environments, including indoors and outdoors, the module demonstrated its ability to provide accurate positioning information within an acceptable error margin. By integrating GPS data with other sensor information, the cane can offer comprehensive navigation assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful design and implementation of the STM32-based smart cane&amp;rsquo;s GPS module validate its effectiveness in providing accurate positioning and navigation capabilities. The experimental results underscore the module&amp;rsquo;s potential to enhance the mobility and safety of cane users. Future research could further optimize algorithms and technologies to increase the GPS module&amp;rsquo;s accuracy and robustness and expand the smart cane&amp;rsquo;s functionalities and application fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;26-wifi-module&#34;&gt;2.6 WIFI Module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.6.1 Hardware Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrating a WiFi module into the intelligent cane as an assistive device enables wireless connectivity and data exchange, providing a smarter, more convenient mobility experience for people with mobility challenges. This section aims to design a WiFi module based on the STM32 microcontroller for efficient and reliable wireless communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thorough hardware selection and design, a WiFi module fitting the smart cane&amp;rsquo;s requirements was chosen, with designed interfaces for STM32 microcontroller connectivity and antenna circuits. Following the WiFi module&amp;rsquo;s operational principles and protocols, a driver and communication protocol stack were developed for the STM32, ensuring data transfer reliability and connection management. Various tests were conducted in different scenarios to evaluate the module&amp;rsquo;s performance, stability, and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardware design involved analyzing and selecting a compact, low-power, and stable performance WiFi module from the market. The WiFi module, a standalone device with an antenna and transceiver, connects to the STM32 through serial communication interfaces like UART, SPI, or I2C. Adapting the module to the smart cane&amp;rsquo;s specific needs involved designing compatible interfaces and considering signal transmission stability and anti-interference capabilities. Additionally, an appropriate antenna was selected and optimally placed to achieve good signal coverage and sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WiFi module allows the smart cane to scan for and connect to nearby wireless networks. Users can input the desired WiFi network name and password through the cane&amp;rsquo;s interface (e.g., buttons, touch screen) to establish a connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.6.2 Software Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software design includes developing a driver for the STM32 to communicate and transfer data with the WiFi module. The communication protocol stack, including TCP/IP, UDP, and HTTP, was coded to ensure reliable data transfer and network connection management. Algorithms for error handling and correction were also developed to enhance data transmission stability and reliability. Through the WiFi module, the smart cane can transmit and communicate data over the internet, engaging in communication with remote servers to transfer location data, navigation instructions, health data, etc. Moreover, the WiFi module facilitates data exchange and communication within a local network with other devices (e.g., smartphones, computers). It also enables remote control capabilities. Users can operate the cane&amp;rsquo;s functions, such as navigation settings and alarm triggers, using mobile applications or other remote control devices. Additionally, the Wi-Fi module can connect to cloud services, enabling cloud storage, data synchronization, and remote updates. Security is a significant concern when establishing Wi-Fi connections. Appropriate security measures, such as encryption protocols (e.g., WPA2), authentication, and access control, should be implemented to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of wireless communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.6.3 Implementation Effect of the Wi-Fi Module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assess the performance of the Wi-Fi module in the STM32-based smart cane, a series of experiments were conducted. These experiments covered the wireless coverage range of the module, the speed of data transmission, and the reliability of the module under various environmental conditions. The results showed that the Wi-Fi module successfully established stable connections and provided reliable data transmission within the designated range, performing satisfactorily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design and implementation of the Wi-Fi module in the STM32-based smart cane demonstrate its effectiveness in providing wireless connectivity and supporting advanced functionalities. The experimental results confirm the module&amp;rsquo;s performance in terms of wireless coverage, data transmission speed, and reliability. Integrating the Wi-Fi module with the STM32 microcontroller enhances the smart cane&amp;rsquo;s functionality, enabling seamless data communication and interaction with other devices or cloud services. This module offers reliable wireless connectivity for smart cane users, facilitating more convenient and efficient data exchange and interaction experiences. Future research could further optimize the performance of the Wi-Fi module, expand its functionalities and application scenarios, and explore wireless collaboration with other intelligent devices to enhance the practicality and user experience of the smart cane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;experimental-results-and-conclusions&#34;&gt;Experimental Results and Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;31-experimental-results&#34;&gt;3.1 Experimental Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the circuit was realized and set up, a series of simulated experiments were conducted. The corridor with classrooms on both sides was chosen as the experimental venue, with experimenters using a board as an obstacle. The experimenters, blindfolded and holding the guide cane, walked forward. The guide cane emitted corresponding voice warnings when the distance to an obstacle, either in front or at the bottom, was less than or equal to 1.5 meters. When the temperature sensor power was activated by the experimenters, the environmental temperature was voice broadcasted; deactivating the power stopped the broadcast. When water was sprinkled on the ground, there was no alarm for a small amount of water, but an alarm was triggered for water accumulation of 1cm or more. When experimenters placed their finger on the fingerprint recognition module, the guide cane was successfully unlocked. The mobile phone connected to the WIFI module could display the GPS positioning of the guide cane. If the experimenter fell to the ground and remained there for more than 5 minutes, the buzzer alarm was timely activated. The alarm could be canceled by pressing a button. The display screen on the guide cane could effectively show weather information and payment codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;32-conclusions&#34;&gt;3.2 Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simulated experiments verified the practicality and operability of the guide cane, proving that it can effectively guide blind individuals to avoid obstacles both above and below, detect temperatures and the presence of water on the road, and promptly alarm. Additionally, the fingerprint module ensured the information security of the guide cane, while the display screen facilitated the daily life of the blind by showing payment codes. The voice broadcast greatly facilitated the travel of the blind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
