<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronic | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/electronic/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/electronic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Electronic</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Electronic</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/electronic/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>f) Electronic system design</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-background&#34;&gt;Project Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intelligent vehicle, or wheeled mobile robot, integrates multiple functions such as environmental sensing, planning and decision-making, and autonomous driving into a comprehensive system. Aimed at enhancing future lifestyles with smarter solutions, this technology is applicable not only in military contexts but also in scientific research, intelligent rescue, and more. The vehicle&amp;rsquo;s mechanical structure comprises the body, wheels, speed sensors, rotational axles, equipped with a power driver and a camera module for environmental data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;design-scheme-overview&#34;&gt;Design Scheme Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employing a PID control algorithm and a CCD linear camera for black line guidance detection, processed by an LM393 comparator for microcontroller-based data collection and image recognition, this design enables path identification. Motor drive is facilitated by the PC33886 model, with speed measured by direct photoelectric sensors, and data displayed on an LCD screen. Four button keys are utilized for parameter settings, enhancing the user interface for onsite debugging. The project ingeniously incorporates a mix of photonic, mechanical, and wireless communication technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structural-and-system-design&#34;&gt;Structural and System Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the principles of autonomous guide robot systems, the intelligent car is capable of autonomously recognizing and following predetermined paths. The main control module uses the STC89C51 microcontroller, focusing on centralized control and modular design, incorporating infrared sensor line tracking and trajectory detection modules. The mechanical structure is designed to minimize external light interference, ensuring balanced and stable navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardware-system-construction&#34;&gt;Hardware System Construction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system&amp;rsquo;s hardware includes the STM32F103 microcontroller as the main control module, along with power, motor drive, infrared obstacle avoidance, control terminal, and wireless video monitoring modules. This setup ensures reliable power supply and effective control over the vehicle&amp;rsquo;s dynamic monitoring functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;programming-challenges-and-solutions&#34;&gt;Programming Challenges and Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report also delves into the learning process for programming the STM32 microcontroller, including clock initialization, mobility function implementation, PID algorithm development, steering functionality, Bluetooth serial port configuration, and PID debugging. By exploring sensor detection, PWM output for motor driving, speed detection, and serial communication, the project overcame various developmental challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-summary&#34;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through teamwork, we successfully assembled the intelligent car and achieved the line-tracking task. Throughout the project, we solved multiple technical problems, gaining an in-depth understanding of the working principles of intelligent cars and mastering STM32 related skills. This experience not only enhanced our practical abilities but also strengthened our team collaboration spirit. This course has provided us with invaluable and enriching learning, contributing significantly to our academic and practical growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>g) Proteus electronic system design and simulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;design-description&#34;&gt;Design description:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic function of this design is to collect temperature and humidity, then collect light intensity (as the input signal part), and then display these three values on the digital tube (as the output signal part). Then set the upper limit value in the program, and the buzzer will alarm when the upper limit value is exceeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the simulation part, a light bulb and a photoresistor are used to simulate a light sensor. The voltage across the photoresistor is obtained to represent the light intensity. Then an operational amplifier is used to make the change in light intensity and voltage within a certain range have a linear relationship. At this time, the light obtained Strong is just an analog value, which is then input to the PF0 port of ATmega64 for the next step of analog-to-digital conversion; in addition, similar to the photosensitive part, the temperature sensitive part uses a light bulb plus a thermosensitive resistor to simulate the temperature sensor; the humidity part uses pulse voltage frequency simulation Humidity, the humidity value we obtain at this time is already a digital quantity, which can be directly input into the PD6 port of ATmega64. The quantities we input will be used for subsequent display on the LM016L and for alarming when the set threshold is exceeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, in the output part, we use LM016L for display, which displays digital quantities, and then switches the display and sets the alarm threshold through buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the working voltage part, except the buzzer alarm which uses DC +12V voltage, the rest uses the DC +5V voltage output by LM7805. Then the working voltage of ATmega64 is 4.5V to 5.5V, the working voltage of temperature and humidity sensor is 5V, the maximum working voltage of photodiode is generally 10 to 50V, the best working voltage of LM016L module is 5V, whichever of the above devices can work The voltage is 5V as the supply voltage. And due to the limitations of the device LM016L, the operating current is 2mA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;electrical-schematic-diagram&#34;&gt;Electrical schematic diagram:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/1oRed6YiyKL5gED.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;7.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;printed-board-diagram&#34;&gt;Printed board diagram:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/Oj1hZHAzsKUfklv.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;8.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>h) Communication Principle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-functionality&#34;&gt;I. Functionality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;transmitter-side&#34;&gt;Transmitter Side:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user inputs the mathematical expression to be calculated through buttons.  The expression can include basic operations such as addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division (complex calculations can be added similarly). Then, the process of Encoding → Modulating → Sending is executed. After sending, the device immediately enters a waiting mode, awaiting a response from the receiver side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;receiver-side&#34;&gt;Receiver Side:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The receiver side is in a waiting state from the start. Upon receiving a signal, it automatically performs demodulation, calculation, encoding, modulation, and then sends a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;other-buttons&#34;&gt;Other Buttons:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Carrier 1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Carrier 2&amp;rdquo; buttons can display the waveform of the carrier on the right side of the image. The processes of encoding, modulation, and reception will be shown on the waveform graph on the right side, displaying the time-domain waveform. The introduction button provides a simple explanation of the principles. The &amp;ldquo;stop&amp;rdquo; button is used to interrupt detection, and the &amp;ldquo;out&amp;rdquo; button is used to exit this window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-principle-and-implementation&#34;&gt;II. Principle and implementation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;encoding&#34;&gt;Encoding&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Encoding:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in Figure, the wireless calculator is designed with 16 input buttons, which is the 4th power of 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Channel Encoding:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why use Hamming encoding for the information bits? The answer is that Hamming encoding is an efficient linear block code capable of correcting single-bit errors. The 7,4 Hamming code adds three check bits to a group of 4-bit information bits and can correct minor errors through the calculation of syndromes or correction factors. This enhances the communication system&amp;rsquo;s resistance to interference, as detailed in the textbook on page 261.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frame Synchronization and Protection Codes:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of frame synchronization is to determine the sampling moments for each bit. The frame synchronization code here is used to inform the receiving end when the valid information begins and to establish the starting moment for sampling. Barker codes, with their sharp autocorrelation peak, facilitate identification and minimize the likelihood of false synchronization. The receiver&amp;rsquo;s identification method is also simple, hence the choice of Barker codes as the true synchronization codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the variable length of the information bits transmitted in this system, the receiver cannot determine when to end sampling, so a Barker code is also added at the end to accurately extract the middle information bits. The role of the protection code is to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;provide energy variation for the receiver to detect energy changes, and to prevent the delay in calculation from omitting useful information bits, offering the computer a buffer time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;modulation&#34;&gt;Modulation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modulation method is 2FSK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the sampling frequency needs to be determined. It is best if the sampling frequency is consistent with the MATLAB sound function, hence 8000Hz is chosen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, determine the bit transmission rate RB. Generally, a lower transmission rate results in higher accuracy but lower efficiency. Thus, a compromise is chosen at 100Hz. Given a sampling frequency of 8000, this means
fs=100Hz and each bit is expanded to 80 samples (8000/80 = 100Hz). The normalized frequency is 0.025π, and the time-domain waveform and spectrum of the transmitted bits are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, determine the frequencies for carrier 1 and carrier 2. When selecting frequencies, it&amp;rsquo;s important that the main lobes of the frequency spectra for carrier 1 and carrier 2 overlap as little as possible after modulation. The width of the lobes on either side is fs, so there should be a gap of 2fs between the two carrier frequencies. Considering phase continuity, the frequencies should have an even ratio to simplify calculations and programming without the need to consider phase discontinuities. Furthermore, they should be below half the sampling frequency to satisfy the sampling theorem, i.e., below 4000Hz. Hence, 1000Hz and 2000Hz are chosen, with normalized frequencies of 0.25π and 0.5π respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modulation method involves modulating each bit (before expansion) into 80 points (corresponding to a sampling frequency of 8000, or 100Hz). If a bit is 1, then a 2000Hz sine wave repeating 20 times is used as the modulation waveform (2000/20=100Hz); if a bit is 0, then a 1000Hz sine wave repeating 10 times is used (1000/10=100Hz).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reception-and-demodulation&#34;&gt;Reception and Demodulation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the steps for demodulation are the reverse of those for modulation and correspond one-to-one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reception uses an energy detection method, which is simply a process of multiplying corresponding elements of matrices and summing them up to check if they reach a threshold value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2FSK Non-coherent Demodulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice of non-coherent demodulation for 2FSK arises from the fact that coherent demodulation involves a multiplication process. At the selection stage, non-coherent demodulation was chosen because if it involves multiplication, the chance of coding errors increases significantly, whereas non-coherent demodulation is primarily determined by filters, making its implementation simpler. Thus, non-coherent demodulation was used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To decode, first locate the Barker codes at both ends and extract the data in between. This is done by comparing each received bit with the Barker code, using the XOR method to count the differences. If there are three or fewer differences from the Barker code, it is considered a match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The removal of the Barker codes is followed by 7,4 Hamming decoding, which includes error correction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result represents a complete transmission process from the sender: encoding &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; modulation &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; transmission, and from the receiver: detection &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; demodulation &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; decoding. Afterwards, the receiver decodes the source information according to the bit information, calculates the result, and then performs encoding &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; modulation &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; transmission back to the sender. The process is generally the same as described above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i) Electronic system design and simulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/external-project-copy-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was particularly engaged by the electronic system design courses, since I could build up my practical capability and build on the theoretical. We also the used single chip microcomputer 80C51F020 to generate a digital sine wave that could control the amplitude and frequency changes via keyboard and output stable sine wave by 12-bit DAC. From the design and simulation of the hardware circuit, to the layout and welding of the circuit board, and then to the design and debugging of the software part of the MCU, we designed a digital synthesis signal device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synopsis-of-digital-synthesizer-creation&#34;&gt;Synopsis of Digital Synthesizer Creation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;objective-and-innovation&#34;&gt;Objective and Innovation:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the core of this endeavor was the ambition to construct a digital synthesizer capable of generating sine waves, with enhanced user control over amplitude and frequency modulation. The project&amp;rsquo;s cornerstone was the adept use of the 80C51F020 microcontroller, showcasing an astute application of digital-to-analog conversion techniques to engineer precise and adjustable electronic signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-mastery-and-application&#34;&gt;Technical Mastery and Application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;signal-range-and-modulation&#34;&gt;Signal Range and Modulation:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project&amp;rsquo;s specification to adjust signal frequencies between 1Hz to 100Hz, alongside amplitude variations from 0.3V to 3Vp-p, demonstrates a rigorous and calculated approach to electronic signal manipulation. This precision underscores the team&amp;rsquo;s dedication to creating adaptable and user-centric electronic solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;microcontroller-utilization&#34;&gt;Microcontroller Utilization:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employing the C8051F020&amp;rsquo;s 12-bit DAC was a strategic choice, spotlighting the project&amp;rsquo;s innovative use of microcontroller capabilities to ensure signal accuracy. This decision reflects a harmonious fusion of software-driven logic with the tangible dynamics of hardware execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;convergence-of-hardware-and-software-design&#34;&gt;Convergence of Hardware and Software Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;comprehensive-system-development&#34;&gt;Comprehensive System Development:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project narrative delineates the transition from conceptual circuit design to the practical assembly and detailed microcontroller software debugging. This extensive process underscores the team&amp;rsquo;s proficiency in electronic system realization, encompassing a broad spectrum of engineering skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;advanced-signal-processing&#34;&gt;Advanced Signal Processing:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizing MATLAB for generating sine wave samples and their quantization for DAC implementation is indicative of an advanced approach to signal processing. This methodology bridges theoretical concepts with real-world technological applications, enriching the project&amp;rsquo;s technical depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;design-requirements-function-and-indicator-description&#34;&gt;Design requirements (function and indicator description)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signal frequency range: 1Hz-100Hz; step: 1Hz; accuracy: +/-5% (the above indicators are measured at room temperature)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signal amplitude: 0.3V-3Vp-p; step: 0.1V; accuracy: +/-10% (the above indicators are measured at room temperature)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load capacity: can drive 10 ohm pure group load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequency and amplitude can be displayed through LED digital tube (can be displayed alternately through indicator lights)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective when the keyboard is raised&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-hardware-schematic-diagram&#34;&gt;System hardware schematic diagram&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following figure shows the simulation schematic diagram on Tina
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/O4shf9ECuUZPRji.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;9.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-technical-points-of-hardware-modules&#34;&gt;Key technical points of hardware modules&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dac-module&#34;&gt;DAC module&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experiment uses C8051F020 built-in 12-bit voltage output DAC, which has the following main features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The voltage reference of each DAC is provided at the VREFD or VREF pin.

Each DAC has a flexible output update mechanism that allows seamless full-scale changes and supports jitter-free output updates.

The data and control interface between the MCU and each comparator and DAC are implemented through special registers
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main indicators of DAC: 12bit resolution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Output setup time: 10us

Output voltage range: 0~VREF-1LSB

Output short circuit current: 15mA
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we tried to use Tina simulation software to build a DAC module that can output stepped sine waves, so that we can verify the feasibility of subsequent modules on the software, especially the quality of the filtering effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;filter-module&#34;&gt;Filter module&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/bzpsqN2tVjuGJAP.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;10.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

Generate a second-order Bessel low-pass filter through filter pro, and the parameter settings are as shown in the figure below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This circuit module generates a clock signal, DACO generates a ladder signal, inputs an eighth-order ladder wave through DACO, and CLK inputs a clock signal of 100:1 (clock signal frequency: sinusoidal signal frequency) to achieve the function of the filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) The signal frequency is adjustable.
The signal frequency is controlled by changing the frequency of the ladder signal generated by DACO and changing the frequency of the signal in the CLK generation formula through program control. The highest frequency output that can be achieved is 2000Hz, and it has stable frequency output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) Signal phase modulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By selecting the DACO phase to output, digital phase modulation is achieved. The 0 phase is used when the number is 0 and the T phase is used when the number is 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;power-amplifier-module&#34;&gt;Power amplifier module&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/hE6OuMApUNWHior.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;11.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

A DC-blocking capacitor C4 is added before the power amplifier module to prevent the filter module and the power amplifier from affecting each other. , in order to prevent the base current from being too large and burning the transistor due to too small resistance, a 40k protection resistor is connected in series. The static operating current is determined by adjusting the resistance of this series resistor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of the C5 and C4 capacitors is to isolate the DC path and allow AC to pass. The signal amplified by the transistor is coupled to R5 and R7 through C5, where test points are set for output testing. Due to the presence of R5, there will be a certain emitter voltage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;single-power-supply&#34;&gt;Single power supply&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/YRwd5IVh1yurUHq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;12.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

Dual power supply is suitable for AC signals to pass through, while single power supply is more suitable for unipolar (DC). However, considering the laboratory facilities and other reasons, the following processing can make it suitable for AC signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R4 and R2 divide the voltage to obtain 1/2 V+. This voltage is added to the input terminal of the op amp. Since C1 is equivalent to an open circuit under DC conditions, this 1/2 V+ only obtains a single gain. The output terminal of the op amp That is, the same voltage is obtained. Capacitors are used at the output for AC coupling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an AC signal is input, the output of the op amp forms a corresponding AC signal with 1/2 V+ as the baseline, and this AC signal can gain gain.
Therefore, the single-supply power supply tries to establish 1/2 of V+ to obtain a single gain from the DC, and uses capacitors at the output for AC coupling so that it can also be suitable for AC signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-software-block-diagram-and-overview&#34;&gt;System software block diagram and overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;software-flow-chart&#34;&gt;Software flow chart:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.loli.net/2024/03/27/thJS1DaUprzZ3my.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;13.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;system-software-overview&#34;&gt;System software overview:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system is based on the signal waveform generator of the C8051F020 microcontroller. It uses the DAC0 of the microcontroller to control the output voltage. It uses timer 0, working mode 1, and a 16-bit timer. The count value of the timer is reloaded every time it is interrupted, and the timer is reloaded according to the advance settings. A certain sine wave sampling array is used to change the DAC0 output to obtain a sine waveform, and then the final waveform is obtained through hardware circuit filtering and power amplifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;①Generate sine wave sampling array&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use MATLAB to obtain sine wave sampling data within a period. In order to normalize the amplitude, we first set the sine wave amplitude to 1V, sample 256 points, and then use MATLAB&amp;rsquo;s quantizer function to map the value to 0~4096. In this way, when changing the amplitude of the sine wave, multiply the array value by the voltage value to get the corresponding voltage amplitude. To change the frequency, you only need to set the corresponding timer period and output the array value after changing the voltage amplitude in sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;②System initialization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;③Frequency, amplitude addition and subtraction step control and display&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since step control only requires 4 keys for frequency addition and subtraction and amplitude addition and subtraction, we only use the first row of the keyboard. The two on the left are for frequency addition and subtraction, and the two on the right are for amplitude addition and subtraction. The principle of changing the frequency and amplitude is to first change the flag bit, and then change the size according to the flag bit. This makes the code structure clearer, and can display the corresponding frequency amplitude according to the flag bit. The four-digit digital tube on the left displays the frequency, and the two on the right Bit display amplitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more important part is the frequency change. Because of the limitations of the clock frequency and DAC settling time, different numbers of sampling points need to be set. We set it to 256 sampling points when the frequency is less than 100Hz. When the frequency is greater than 100Hz and less than 500Hz, There are 64 sampling points. When the frequency is greater than 500Hz, there are 32 sampling points. The specific algorithm is: timer count value = 65536 - clock frequency ÷ (number of sampling points × frequency size). For example, 1KHz, clock frequency is 2M, timer count value = 65536-200000÷(32×1000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;④Interrupt service routine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interrupt service program is used to reload the timer count value regularly, take out the next sine wave sample value according to the frequency step parameter, change the DAC output voltage, and then scan a digital tube every ten interrupts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital Signal Generator project exemplifies the seamless integration of theoretical knowledge and practical expertise in electronic system design. By navigating the complexities of signal generation, modulation, and the synthesis of hardware with software, the team not only underscored their engineering acumen but also embraced a philosophy of lifelong learning and innovation. This project serves not just as a showcase of applied electronic principles but as a testament to the ongoing journey of knowledge acquisition and application in the engineering realm, paving the way for future advancements in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
